PHARMACIST, PHARMACY OPERATIONS CLINICAL MANAGER

Professional Background

Pharmacist with 16 years of pharmacy operations experience in medical oncology supporting practice operations, clinical trial research, drug procurement, drug selection, inventory management, regimen financial analysis, negotiating contracts and budgets, managing relations with pharmaceutical sponsors, suppliers and internal customers. This experience is complemented by strong analytical, organizational, management and leadership, planning, communication and computer skills. \hat{A} Provided loyal support \hat{A} to \hat{A} oncology practices \hat{A} within USOncology, Rocky Mountain Cancer Centers, \hat{A} and Cancer Center of Colorado Springs as they were acquired \hat{A} by McKesson Specialty Health where \hat{A} I am currently employed today. \hat{A} \hat{A} \hat{A}

Professional Experience

10/2015 - Current

Massachusetts Institute Of Technology - Boston, MA Pharmacist, Pharmacy Operations Clinical Manager

- Responsible for Pharmacy Operations support for USON CSA practices in the West and Mountain Regions.Â
- Conduct quarterly on site practice visits to provide initiative, clinical, operational and economic summaries of pharmacy initiatives. Â
- Develop Action Plans for each practice as needed for optimal initiative performance.Â
- Support The Network growth by on-boarding new practices and IMAs to pharmacy initiatives and operations.Â

01/2010 - 11/2013

Iqvia Holdings Inc - Albany, GA Director of Research

- Oversight of daily operations of clinical research for 12 medical oncology/radiation oncology locations and 30 clinical research staff.
- RMCC participates in over 70 USOncology Research, direct pharmaceutical and radiation oncology investigator initiated clinical trials and enrolls over 280 patients each year.
- Directly responsible for trial activity to maintain quality, integrity, and financial stability.
- Collaborate with USOncology Research, all members of the RMCC leadership team, Clinical Research Organizations and pharmaceutical sponsors for department operational success.

08/2008 - 01/2010

Grane - Bethlehem, PA Clinical Pharmacist

Responsible for clinical oncology pharmacy activities to include oversight of chemotherapy preparation, EMR implementation, clinical trail
research drug accountability, drug financial analysis, chemotherapy regimen preparation and approval.

10/2006 - 08/2008

Fraser - Richfield, MN Clinical Research Manager/Pharmacist

- The Cancer Center of Colorado Springs joined RMCC and USOncology in August 2006.
- Acted as office administrator and clinical supervisor during transition.
- Clinical Research duties include: Protocol contracting and budgeting for pharmaceutical trials, protocol review, and supervision of Colorado Springs and Pueblo clinical trial staff.
- Pharmacy duties include: pathway review, oversight of pharmacy technicians, P&T committee presentations, drug inventory management, financial analysis preparation and presentation to physicians. PQE participation.

08/2000 - 03/2012

Vireo Health - Woodbury, MN Consultant Pharmacist

- Preform duties of consultant pharmacist.
- Manage drug formulary and form development.
- Assist physicians in narcotic control and overall inventory management.
- Participate in quality assurance and improvement.
- Available to center clinical staff for clinical or operational issues.

08/1999 - 08/2006

Health Alliance Of Hudson Valley - Mount Kisco, NY Manager

- Responsible for daily operations.
- Maintain cost control through drug formulary management for Cancer Center of Colorado Springs.
- Develop relationships with GPOs, pharmaceutical representatives, and drug distributors to control costs and educate staff.
- Established local physician network to maximize profitability through GPO contracting and performance.
- Perform viability and profitability analysis.
- Clinical Trial Program Director.
- Anticoagulation clinical pharmacist.
- Assist in drug billing and collections.
- Assist in negotiating managed are contracts.

Vireo Health - Amado, AZ Pharmacy Manager

- Responsible for the development and implementation of home infusion program in a joint venture with Abbott Laboratories.
- Extensively involved in contract pricing and negotiations to third party payors.
- Assist in sales and marketing services to payors, physicians, home health agencies, hospices and discharge planners.
- Inform hospital physician and specialty groups of advances in home infusion services through periodic presentations.
- Recruit and train home infusion employees.
- Supervise a staff of twelve home infusion employees.
- Develop operating budget and manage department within budget parameters.
- Prepare department for JCAHO accreditation survey.

10/1994 - 05/1995

Response Technologies Inc, The Impact Center Of Colorado Springs - City, STATE Pharmacist

- Responsible for daily pharmacy operations.
- Compounded high dose chemotherapy for Clinical Trails and Protocols for chemotherapy induced peripheral stem cell mobilization and high dose chemotherapy induction.
- Clinical trials resulted in negative outcomes and practice was closed.

09/1991 - 10/1994

NMC HomeCare - City, STATE Pharmacy Manager

- Responsible for overall pharmacy operations of home infusion pharmacy.
- Clinically monitored drug regimes.
- Hired and trained personnel.
- Maintained pharmacy operations in compliance with state, local, and federal regulations.
- Assured JCAHO compliance and accreditation.
- Marketed pharmacy services to payors, physicians, home health agencies, long term care facilities and discharge planners.
- Provided training to home health agencies on home infusion services, pumps and supplies.

Education and Training

May 1991

Creighton University School of Pharmacy City, State Bachelor of Science: Pharmacy

Registered Pharmacist Colorado-Active

License Number 13322

Certifications

Certified in Healthcare Research Compliance

December 2012

Skills

Lean Six Sigma: Blue Belt Training 2010, Green Belt Training 2011

Proficient in Excel and other Microsoft products.

Proficient in iKnowmed G1 and Lynx Mobile.

Strategic, Detailed, Multi-Task Management, Drug Financial Analysis, Relator, Customer Service, Client Relations, Expense Control, Project Management